想打赢过你还嫩了点  萨姆
You don't have the juice to take me on,sam.
不  你的能力  你越来越得心应手了
No,your abilities -- you're getting flabby.
是  那我怎么再增强我的能力
Yeah,so how do I tone up?
你知道你要做什么
You know what you got to do.
不  我不能再这么做了
No,i'm not doing that anymore.
-萨姆  -我说了不了
- Sam...  - I said no.
单手切牌
Charlier cut.
你真的很棒
Wow. you're really good.
是诶  好棒啊
Yeah,great.
换个别的呢
Hey,show us another.
喝你的饮料吧 万斯
Finish your drink,vance.
这是个简单的洗牌方式
This is a simple riffle shuffle.
来个纸牌魔术吧
Do a card trick for me.
开始了  超人杰伊
Ooh,here we go -- the incredible jay.
没问题 这位小姐
All right,young lady
你来告诉我什么时候停
would you please tell me when to stop?
停
Stop.
这是你的牌
This is your card.
记住哦
Commit it to memory. hmm?
真是难以置信 杰伊
That's incredible,jay.
别跟个混蛋一样
Don't be a jerk.
好了  现在...看到你的牌了吗
Right,now... do you see your card?
没  认不出来
Um,no,i don't.
没  纸牌说"没"
No,the cards say "no."
-查查他的口袋 -看在上帝的份上 万斯
Check his pocket. for god's sake,vance.
就看看  就看看那他妈的口袋
Oh,just check -- check the damn pocket!
那么  如果你要拿走...
So,if you then would remove...
这是你的牌吗
Is this your card?
为什么你那么贱
why are you so mean?
你为什么就要死盯着这位老先生呢
Can't you just leave the old guy alone?
他画眼线了吗
Is he wearing eyeliner?
不知道
Can't tell.
我被这荧光灯弄得眼花了
I'm blinded by all the sterling silver.
追光灯要射向我
The light has to find me!
明白了吗  要射向我
Get it?! it -- it has to find me!
真是个傻逼
what a douche bag.
你们就不能消停一下么
Oh,would guys give it a rest?
我被你们搞得头痛了
You're giving me a headache.
怎么了 杰伊
Oh,come on,jay.
他这样当然会误导我们
His misdirect is
他屁股扭得就跟第八大道上的妓女一样
shaking his ass like an 8th avenue hooker.
以前都是讲究技术的
Used to be about skill.
是啊 从前
Yeah,used to be. used to be.
听听你们俩说的话  真是可悲
Listen to the you two. it's pathetic.
苦唧唧的老人回想以前的光辉岁月
Bitter,old men talking about the glory days.
你知道什么  这个傻逼不是个笑料
You know what? this douche bag isn't the joke.
我们才是
We are.
你在说谁是笑料呢
Hey,who you calling a joke?
我  就我一个
Me,for one.
那以前是我们
That used to be us.
你知道  也许他是个傻逼
You know,maybe he is a douche bag
但是他在主台上表演
but he's playing the main stage,
我们却连助理都请不起
And we can't even afford an assistant.
我们他妈的在做什么
What the hell are we doing?
我们过的很好啊
We're doing all right.
不  我们不是
No,we're not.
我们又苦  又老
We're sad,we're old...
而且我们都快死了
And we're dying.
杰伊
Jay.
我今晚要玩死亡魔术
I'm gonna do the table of death tonight.
不要  杰伊  别发疯
No. no,you're not,jay. don't be crazy.
你上次试的时候差点就没命了
You almost killed yourself the last time you tried it.
而且那是30年前的事了
And that was 30 years ago!
就算我丧命了  谁在乎呢
Oh,who cares if it kills me?
至少  我还能得个头条
At least I'll go out with a headline.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
你将要看到的  不是小花招也不是幻觉
What you are about to see is not a trick or an Illusion
这只是胆量与技巧的显示
-- simply a display of daring and dexterity.
现在  小姐  请检查一下封条
Now,young lady,if you'll please check the bindings.
你能发现他们很真实  很紧
You'll see they're very real,very tight.
谢谢
Thank you.
你可以回去坐下了
You may take your seat.
它们的确很紧
Damn straight they're tight.
你确定你能让他们松开吗
You sure you can slip them?
一个小时后就要开演了 万斯
Show's in an hour,vance.
试着准时点
Try to be on time.
这不是个小花招  好吗
This isn't a trick,okay?
我不耍小花招
I-i-i don't do tricks.
这是关于恶魔与天使
This is a demonstration about demons and angels
爱情与色欲
love and lust...
真是个傻逼
What a douche bag.
...所有这一些都在我脑海中交错的展现
...all that stuff mixed up in my head.
那是杰布·德克斯特
That's jeb dexter.
我都不想知道你怎么知道的
I don't even want to know how you know that.
他很有名...之类的
He's famous...kind of.
因为什么  因为他娘娘腔吗
For what,douchebaggery?
不管这个看起来有多扭曲  别碰我  好么
...how messed up it gets,don't touch me,okay?
为了你们的自身安全
For your own safety.
滚回地狱去  恶魔
Go back to hell,demon!
这是你的牌吗
Is this your card?
你在开玩笑吧  装恶魔附体
Oh,you got to be kidding me. a fake demon possession?
我真不敢相信人们居然信这一套瞎话
I can't believe people actually fall for that crap.
这不是瞎话
It's not all crap.
这里哪个部分不是胡话
What part of that was not a steaming pile of b.s.?
好吧  那是谎话  但那不仅仅是魔术
Okay,that was crap,but that's not all magicians.
这是需要技巧的
It takes skill.
对  对  我忘了
Oh,right. right. I forgot.
你就是很喜欢这类东西  不是吗
You were actually into this stuff,weren't you?
我是说  你  你有  好像是  一副纸牌和一根魔术棒
I mean,you had -- you had,like,a deck of cards and a wand.
兄弟  那是我13岁的时候了  那是人成长的一个阶段
Dude,i was 13. it was a phase.
只是  让我起鸡皮疙瘩
Just -- it bugs me.
实际上  触怒我
Actually,it offends me.
知道吗  人们热衷于魔鬼戏法和魔术
You know,playing at demons and magic,
殊不知那些玩意可以让他们丧命
When the real thing will kill you bloody.
像某男子被10道利器刺死
Like a guy who drops dead of 10 stab
外衣却完好无缺吗
Wounds without a single tear in his shirt?
正是
That's what I'm talking about.
你知道你老板有和谁结仇吗
So,did your boss have any enemies that you know of?
他的仇敌  多着呢
Vance had plenty of enemies.
怎么说
How so?
他偷取别的魔术师的戏法
He would steal from other magicians...
一向如此
All the time.
都偷些什么
What would he steal?
舞台效果  近景技巧  能抄则抄呗
Stage effects,closeup techniques -- anything he could get his hands on.
这不足以造成杀人动机吧
Is that enough to get him killed?
魔术师很在意那些戏法
These guys take this stuff pretty seriously.
你在这
There you are.
你有没在万斯的遗物中找到奇怪的东西
Did you find anything weird in vance's stuff?
例如...符咒
Well...weirder?
事实上  有啊
Matter of fact,I did.
我想  这不是万斯的东西
I'm guessing this didn't belong to vance.
他不喜欢变卡片
He hated card tricks.
也不收集卡片  别说会藏在他的宝贝披肩里
Never wanted them around,let alone in his precious cape.
告诉我  你是怎么变的
You gonna tell me how you did it?
变什么
Did what?
你心知肚明
you know what.
伟大的魔术  永远无法解释
The great ones never give away the "how."
昨天  你还是个可怜的糟老头
Yesterday you were sad,old,and dying.
一眨眼就成了今天的伟大魔术师
Today you're one of the great ones?
别了吧  别懵我
Come on. this is me you're talking to.
你看扁我不能做到
You didn't think I could do it.
没错  杰伊
No,jay,i didn't.
你是我的朋友  挚友
You're my friend,my best friend.
我不希望看到你受伤
I-i just didn't want to see you get hurt.
仅此而已
That's all.
看这里
Look at this.
不赖嘛
Not bad.
不赖
"Not bad"?
我一直在练习如何在牌中抽出A来
I've been working to pull an ace out of the middle of
只是一张  现在我能抽出三张
The deck for years -- just one -- and now I can pull three.
红心A还是没抽到
Still missing the ace of hearts.
我今晚会表演"刽子手"戏法
I want to do the executioner tonight.
你这不是在引火自焚吗
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
绳索逃生而已
It's just a rope slip.
霍迪尼(著名魔术师)也不会尝试这个戏法
Houdini wouldn't try the executioner.
没错
Exactly.
查利  想想  要是我成功了
Think about it,charlie. if I can pull this off...
你别太指望运气了
I think you're pushing your luck.
那不是运气
It wasn't luck.
绝不是
It wasn't.
来  站这里来
Here,stand over there.
我不想这样收场  查利
Let's not end up like this,
一群老东西表演老掉牙的魔术
Charlie -- a couple of old farts doing birthdays and bar mitzvahs.
糟透了
It beats dying.
不是吗
Does it?
你要知道我会为你做任何事
I would do anything for you. you know that.
但我不看着你送死
But I will not watch you die.
恕难出席
I'll miss that show.
不  你会来的
No,you'll be there.
你一直都来看我表演
You're always there for me.
看看你的口袋
Check your pocket.
杰伊 很好嘛
That's good,jay.
这招绝了
That's pretty damn good.
查利  我能行
I can do it,charlie.
我会成功的
I want to do it.
拜托
Please.
那不算什么
it's a lame gig.
我在个破烂酒店  表演什么大众喜爱的魔术
I'm in a fleabag hotel doing this man-of-the-people crap,
但太阳马戏团却在维加斯表演
And freakin' angel's in vegas doing cirque du soleil!
我该到那里表演
That should have been mine.
好了  兄弟  快点吧  我没时间
All right,boys,get it in gear. I don't got all day.
你是弗农·哈斯克尔吗
You vernon haskell?
你是谁
Who's asking?
尤里奇联邦探员
Federal agent ulrich.
调查帕特里克·万斯的死
Looking into the death of patrick vance.
我是杰布·德克斯特  真神了
I'm jeb dexter. this is devil twist.
我们来这里参加国际魔术师大会
We're chilling at the international magicians convention,
正是个好机会
Which is a dope chance to tip my hat
向我的前人脱帽致敬
To the wicked cats who came before me.
昨晚的表演  精彩绝伦  杰姆
Smokin'-hot effect last night,jim.
是杰伊
Jay.
我的名字是杰伊
My name is jay.
随便
Yeah,whatever.
晚点再说
We can loop it later.
不可一世的家伙
What a douche bag.
绝对同意
Couldn't agree more.
你...有见过这个吗
Is,uh... this familiar to you?
没见过
Should it be?
听说你喜欢玩塔罗牌的戏法
Well,i heard that you used tarot cards in your act.
变戏法
My act?
咸丰年的事情了
That was a long time ago.
我很多年不玩牌了
I haven't touched a deck in years,you know...
你知道有谁现在玩纸牌戏法的吗
Do know someone that might use them now?
布利克街上有个男的  他用纸牌
Well,there was a guy down on bleecker street.
是啊
Oh,yeah.
他还在街头卖艺来着
He -- he peddles that kind of specialty stuff.
他和万斯有结怨吗
Did he have a problem with vance?
事实上  一年前  万斯和他有争吵
Matter of fact,vance crossed him about a year ago.
还还他损失了5万美元现金
Probably cost him 50 grand in royalties.
-知道他的地址吗  -布利克街426号
You know the exact address? 426 bleecker.
说找酋长
Ask for chief.
酋长
Chief.
谢谢
Thank you.
我来找酋长
I'm,uh,here to see chief.
呆在这儿
Stay here.
什么也别碰
Don't touch anything.
今晚一定会让你满意的  大男孩
You are really gonna get it tonight,big boy.
你有点误会了
There's been a misunderstanding.
我  想我已经有归属了
I,uh,think I've been had.
你还没有
Oh,you ain't been had...
酋长才是你的归属
Till you been had by the chief.
在开始之前
Oh,and before we get started...
你的口令是什么
...what's your safe word?
你来这儿干什么  露比
What are you doing here,ruby?
这是我要问你的问题
I should be asking you the same thing.
我在干活
I'm working a job.
地狱火就快吞没整个世界了
The whole world's about to be engulfed in hellfire,
而你却在游览美国魔术城
And you're in magictown,u.s.a.
你对魔术有意见吗
You got something against magic?
要是那34个封印没有被打破
That would almost be funny if 34 seals
这倒是挺有意思的  34个了  萨姆
hadn't been broken already. 34,sam.
都已经过半了
That's over halfway.
这场仗天使会输的
The angels are losing this war.
过一天少一天了
Every day is one day closer,
如果某些人不赶紧行动起来
And if someone doesn't do something soon
某些人是指我
and that someone is me?
不然还能是谁
Who else would it be?
我不知道那些封印在哪儿
I don't know where these seals are.
我什么也不知道
I don't know squat.
要不你来告诉我该怎么办
So why don't you tell me where you'd like me to start?
比如说你可以停止到处瞎转
Well,you can quit dicking around,for one.
目标是大鱼  萨姆
Bigger fish,sam.
是不是要等封印全被打破
And if the seals are being broken,
你才会想要追捕罪魁祸首
You might want to go after the one doing the breaking.
莉莉丝
Lilith?
擒贼先擒王
Cut the head off the snake.
只有你才能阻止她  萨姆
You're the only one who can stop her,sam.
所以抓紧时间干掉那个小贱人吧
So step up and kill the little bitch.
是啊  我在浪费时间
Oh,i'm game,believe me.
我不是纠结于那个精神力
It's not the psychic thing I got a problem with.
是  我知道你在纠结什么
Yeah,i know what you got a problem with
但是别娘门儿唧唧的了
but tough.
没别的出路了
It's the only way.
不
No.
你知道
You know,
如果你承认自己其实喜欢这个
This would all be so much easier if
事情会简单很多
You'd just admit to yourself that you like it.
想想你从中得到的感受
That feeling that it gives you.
你不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道
Oh,i don't,huh?
好
Fine.
很简单  路西法复活  末日来临
It's simple -- lucifer rises,the apocalypse starts.
你以为现在自己胜券在握么
You think that you have demons on your hands now?
人类要灭亡了  萨姆
People are gonna die,sam.
成千上万的人
Oceans of people.
等你想清楚了再来找我
So,you just let me know when you're ready.
发现什么好东西没
Find anything interesting?
什么
What?
没有
Uh...no.
你呢
You?
没什么让我再也不愿谈起或想起的事
Nothing I want to talk about or think about ever again.
他在犯傻  你知道的
He's crazy,and you know it.
他说他能行
He says he can do it.
你跟他好好谈过这事吗
Did you even try to talk him out of it?
谈得我都精疲力竭了
Till I was blue in the face.
但是我告诉你  佛农  他的眼睛
But I tell you,vernon,there was...
他的眼睛里有某种东西
There was something in his eyes.
他的眼睛里
"in his eyes."
你俩都疯了
You're both nuts.
酋长
The chief,huh?
怎么了
What's the matter?
酋长不和你的胃口么
The chief not your type?
我可以因为妨碍公务罪
You know,i could have you both arrested
把你们两个都抓起来
for obstruction of justice.
怎么抓  你又不是联邦调查员
How? you're no fed.
我们可是靠行骗谋生的  孩子
We con people for a living,son.
别想用个假徽章来蒙我们
Takes more than a fake badge to get past us.
我投降了
You got us.
是啊  我们  我们实际上是
Yeah,we -- we are actually...
两个怀有明星梦的魔术师
Aspiring magicians.
是的
Yeah,
我们来参加这个大会
We -- we came to the convention
是为了想学点东西
'cause we thought we could learn something.
对  为我们的新表演找点灵感
Yeah,get some ideas for our new show.
什么样的表演
Ooh,what kind of show?
-是  是一个  -一个兄弟秀  -没错
- Well,it's -- it's a -- - it's a brother act. - yeah.
是啊  你知道的  圆圈  白鸽还有  圆圈
Yeah,you know,with the rings and doves and...rings.
女士们先生们  接下来是超人杰伊
Ladies and gentlemen,I'll give you the incredible Jay
你们想学点东西
You want to learn something?
呆在这别动
Stick around.
女士们先生们  你们将要看到一场壮举
Ladies and gentlemen,what you're about to witness
它极度惊心动魄
is a feat so daring,
极度危险  连伟大的霍迪尼也不敢挑战
So dangerous,even the great houdini dared not attempt it.
我将要表演
I give to you...
死囚逃生
The executioner!
先生  正如你所见  这件束缚衣是真货
Now,sir,as you can see,this jacket is the real article.
谢谢你  先生  请回座吧
Thank you,sir. you may take your seat.
现在  我将用一分钟
Now,i will have one minute
60秒  从不可能的险境中逃脱
60 seconds -- to escape certain death.
让我们拭目以待
Let's see if I can do it.
我觉得他办不到
I don't think he's gonna make it.
太精彩了
Oh! that was amazing!
太他妈的精彩了
That was freakin' amazing!
这  不是人能办到的
That was... not humanly possible.
这个名叫杰伊的人
Looks like this guy jay
在七十年代的时候名声大噪
Was a pretty big deal in the '70s.
据说是在"魔术师大陆"  对吗
Which in Magician Land means what,exactly?
大的足够可以做无线电音乐厅
Big enough to play radio city music hall.
那是什么让他终止了他的事业呢
What got him stuck in their "where are they now?" file?
他年纪大了
He got old.
那好吧  那也许"不可思议"的杰伊
Okay,so maybe incredible Jay
是用真实的魔术去创造一个"回归"
is using real magic to stage a comeback.
这有可能
It's possible.
比如说念一些咒语  然后就会死亡传送
Some kind of spell that works a death transference.
那么这跟塔罗牌又有什么关系呢
How does the tarot card mix into it?
这点我也不知道
I don't know.
兄弟
Man...
希望我还没老的时候就已经死了
Hope i die before i get old.
这看起来很残忍  不是么
Whole thing seems brutal,don't it?
你觉得我们也会么
You think we will?
什么
What?
还没步入老年就已经不在人世了
Die before we get old.
难道我们没准备好吗
Haven't we both already?
你知道我什么意思  迪恩
You know what i mean,Dean.
我的意思是  你觉得我们还会继续猎杀恶魔吗
I mean,do you think we'll still be chasing demons
当我们六十岁的时候
When we're 60?
不  我觉得我们之前就会死
No,i think we'll be dead...
比较好
For good.
那你想怎样结束  和特拉维斯一样吗
What? you want to end up like --like Travis?
是吗  还是像戈登一样呢
huh? or Gordon,maybe?
不  那是鲍比
There's Bobby.
你说的对  肯定会有位人之楷模平静的缓缓老去
Oh,yeah,there's a poster child for growing old gracefully.
没准我们会与众不同  迪恩
Maybe we'll be different,Dean.
你走的是哪条路 兄弟
What kind of kool-aid you drinking,man?
萨姆  我们只会在血腥或是悲伤中结束
Sammy,it ends bloody or sad.
这就是我们的命运
That's just the life.
如果我们最后胜利了呢
What if we could win?
什么胜利
"Win"?
如果真有一种办法让我们
If there was a way we could just...
选择一种结局的话
Put an end to all of it.
你有什么事情没告诉我吗
Is there something going on  you're not telling me?
没有  萨姆
- No.  - Sammy.
没有  我的意思是
No. look,i'm st saying...
我只是希望我们有种办法可以
I just wish there was a way we could...
让我们找到根源
Go after the source.
仅此而已
That's all.
把源头砍掉
Cut the head off the snake.
问题在这个源头下面
well,the problem with the snake
有无数个危机在等着我们
is that it has a thousand heads.
那些恶魔们混杂在人群中
evil bitches just keep piling out of the volkswagen.
没错
yeah.
我想你是对的
guess you're right.
你为什么不去跟踪下杰伊看看
why don't you go see if you can track down jay?
我会看看能在这张塔罗牌上发现点什么
i'll see what i can dig up on this tarot card.
女仆发现杰布被吊死在天花板的吊扇上
maid found jeb hanging from the ceiling fan.
警察认为这是自杀
police think it was a suicide.
我可不这样认为
i beg to differ.
一个小小的花招而已
pulled a little sleight of hand  myself.
用德克斯特的身体
on dexter's body?
对 所以我在想这个法术是不是一个死亡的转换
yeah,so i'm thinking if this spell is a death transference,
那么，这些卡片就像黑魔法的目标一样奏效
then these cards work like black-magic targets.
这些受害者之间还有什么其他联系吗
any connection between the victims?
杰布昨天对杰伊大不敬
jeb was a total douche bag to jay yesterday.
那第一个受害者是谁 万斯？
what about the first vic?uh,vance?
我前面问了一下
asked around.
显然 万斯在酒吧问了杰伊那么多尴尬的问题
apparently,vance was heckling jay at the bar
当天他就死了
the day he was killed.
好吧 所以杰伊偷偷的塞了一张卡片进万斯的口袋
okay,so jay sneaks a card into vance's pocket,
完成这个死亡魔术
does the table of death...
接着万斯就被十支剑刺向了胸部
and vance takes 10 swords to the chest.
然后杰伊在绳索逃生魔术中逃脱了 杰布却被吊死了
then jay slips a noose and jeb doesn't.
该死的把戏
hell of a trick.
我想我们是时候找杰伊聊聊了
yeah,i think it's time we had a little chat with jay.
你有啥好消息没
any luck tailing him?
他甩掉了我
he slipped me.
他已经60岁了
he's a 60-year-old.
但他也是一个魔术师
he's a magician.
靠墙
up against the wall!
-天啊你们是什么人 你们想要什么-别动
god,who are you?what do you want?now!
我们知道你一直在干什么
we know what you've been up to.
你在使用一种很恶毒的护身符帮助你完成你的表演
you been working some real bad mojo to jump-start your act.
你在说什么
what?
我不知道你在说什么
i don't know what are you talking about.
听者 我们知道你在这些塔罗牌上下了一些咒语
look,we know you put a spell on those tarot cards.
和真正的魔术相结合
messing with real magic?
真正的魔术
"Real magic"?
够了吧 根本没有真正的魔术
come on,there's no such thing as real magic.
真的吗 是的 相信我
oh,is that so?yeah,believe me.
我这一生都在干这个事情
i've been around this stuff my whole life.
它只不过是
it's all just --
那...那只是幻象  小把戏罢了
It's -- it's illusions.It's tricks.
那...那都是假的
It -- it's all fake.
杰布 德克斯特吊死了  那就只是幻想吗
Jeb Dexter strung up -- was that just an illusion?
你说什么 杰布出事了吗
What? Something happened to Jeb?
他被发现吊死在自己的房间里
He was found hanged in his room.
刚巧就在昨晚你从绞索中逃出生天的时候
Right after you slipped the noose last night.
我不明白你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
求你了...让我走吧
Please...just let me go.
有点不对劲
Something's not right.
通常这个时候他们应该向我们施些要命的咒语
Usually they're whipping some badass hoodoo at us by now.
你觉得该怎么办
What do you want to do?
好吧  那么如果不是他  是谁干的呢
All right,so,if it's not him,who is it?
就算不是杰伊施的黑魔术
Even if Jay's not working the magic,
他还是受益了
he's still getting the reward.
他的表演很受欢迎
His shows are selling out.
好吧
All right.
那么  不管那是什么
So,then,whoever it is,
他们显然就在杰伊的小圈子里
they're obviously in Jay's corner.
好吧  名单上还剩下佛农和查理了
All right,so we got Vernon and Charlie on the list.
还有其他人吗
Anyone else?
我们总该问问他
We could always ask him.
我们应该预见会发生这种事
Guess we should have seen that one coming.
快点  他走不了太远
Come on. He couldn't have gotten that far.
没道理他从我们手中逃脱了
No way he could outrun us.
也许他消失了  我是说  他真的很棒
Maybe he vanished. I mean,he really is good.
又或者他找到后门了
Or he found a back door.
就是他们
That's them!
就是那两个闯入我房间的混球
Those are the two nut jobs that just broke into my room!
不许动  举起手来  放在我们能看到的地方
Hold it!Hands up where we can see it!
他们说我的表演害死人了 他们还说
They said my acting was killing people,they said that
我施的是真魔法  说我是用塔罗牌施咒语
I was using real magic,that I was casting spells on tarot cards.
"真魔法"  那些家伙是蠢货
"Rreal magic." Those guys are nuts.
是你的好运气让你死里逃生的
You're lucky to be alive.
你不会认为...
You don't think...
认为什么
What?
那么  我现在能做到的事...那些纸牌
Well,the things that I can do now -- the cards.
你一生都以摆弄那些纸牌
You've been working the cards your whole life.
那么  那次逃脱怎么说
Well,what about the escapes?
我这30年都不曾从自己的袖子里逃脱过
I haven't been able to slip a pair of cuffs in 30 years.
而且就是以那样的方式 帕特里克 万斯死了
and then there was the way that -- that Patrick Vance died
还有那个杰布 德克斯特
and that Jeb Dexter.
是啊  没什么大不了的
Yeah,no great loss there.
哦  查理  他不该死
Oh,Charlie,he didn't deserve to die.
你与这一切都无关
You had nothing to do with it.
他就在同一晚上吊的
He was hanged the same night
就在我表演刽子手的那一晚
that I performed the executioner.
等一下
Wait a minute.
你不是在说实际上你相信那些人的话吧
Are you telling me that you actually believe those guys?
相信有所谓"真魔法"存在吧
That there was some kind of "real magic" involved?
不
No.
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道  也许有
I don't know,maybe.
今晚我不该再继续了  查理
I shouldn't go on tonight,Charlie.
你在开玩笑吗
Are you kidding me?
你现在上座率百分之百
You have a sold-out house out there.
百分之百
Sold out!
你上一次上座率百分之百是什么时候
When was the last time that happened?
还有那一晚...
The other night...
当我挑战"死亡魔术"的时候
when I was doing the table of death,
我...
I was,um...
我曾想要自杀
...I was gonna kill myself.
我都不知道自己如何逃脱的
And I have no idea how I got out alive.
你做到了
But you did.
不管怎样  你做到了
Somehow,you did.
杰伊
Jay...
在你的时代
when you were in your day
你曾是无所不能的
you were incredible.
"无所不能的大JJ"  你是我见过最棒的
"The incredible Jay."You were the best I ever saw.
现在你的状态又回来了
And now you got it back.
我不知道怎么回事  但那都无所谓
I don't know how,but it doesn't matter.
只要能再看到你回到巅峰时代
Just to see you at the top of your game again.
天哪  让我觉得自己又回到年轻的时候了
Hell,it makes me feel young.
-但是  -没有但是 杰伊
- But - No buts,Jay.
这也许是来自上天的恩赐  我也不知道
This may be maa from heaven,I don't know,
但是不管它是什么
but whatever it is,
你都不要放弃它
you don't throw it away.
杰伊
Jay.
谢谢打电话通知我们
Thanks for dropping the charges.
你不介意告诉我你为什么要这么做吧
You mind telling us why you did it?
我们得谈谈了
We have to talk.
我们第一次相遇的时候我还只是个孩子
I was just a kid when we first met.
我所掌握的只是出老千
All I know was how to cheat at cards.
数不清有多少次查理帮我解围
Charlie got me out of more scrapes than I can count.
天哪  我20岁的时候就该死了
Hell,I would have been dead by the age of 20
如果不是遇到了他
if it hadn't been for him.
他不只是我的朋友
He was more than my friend.
他是我的哥们儿
He was my brother.
我很遗憾 杰伊
I'm sorry,Jay.
你看  我真应该听你们的话
Look,I should have listened to you guys
当你们告诉我我的表演害死人了
When you told me that my show was killing people.
你不是那个扣动扳机的人
Well,you weren't the one pulling the trigger.
是的  但是有人做了  我要找出是谁这样对待查理
Yeah,but someone did,and I want to find out who did this to Charlie,
所以我会照你们说的做任何事
so I'll do whatever you guys say.
只要告诉我怎么做
Just tell me what to do.
杰伊 不管是谁做的...
Jay,whoever's doing this...
他们是喜欢你的
they like you.
他们可能是你亲密的朋友
They're probably close to you.
查理与佛农相处的融洽吗
Did Charlie and Vernon get along?
不
No.
不  不会是佛农
No,it's not vernon.
他是唯一说得通的解释
He's the only one that makes sense.
查理与佛农是你的家人 杰伊
Charlie and Vernon were your family,Jay.
现在查理死了
And now Charlie's gone.
是啊  但是...他们有时争锋相对
Yeah,but...they butted heads sometimes,
但是佛农绝不会做这样的事情
but Vernon could never do something like this.
你看  关于真魔法
See,the thing about real magic
就像是一次尝试
it's a whole lot like crack.
人们尝到甜头就会做出让人吃惊的事来
People do surprising things once they get a taste of it.
你最好他妈的确定这一点
You better be damn sure about this.
佛农是我唯一的依靠了
Vernon's all I got left.
喂
Yeah?
好的
Yeah,okay.
我一会儿就到
I'll be there in two shakes.
不管怎样我有些事要告诉你
I got something to tell you anyway.
喔  这就像个魔术博物馆
Wow.It's like a...magic museum.
你一定会上天堂的
You must be in heaven.
这家伙不是轻装上路
This guy doesn't travel light.
他一生总是漂泊不定
He's been on the road his whole life.
也许他所拥有的一切都在这屋里了
Probably everything he owns is in this room.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
和协会的人探讨过了
Just talked to the head of the convention.
压轴演出的是你
Headliner gig is yours.
什么
What?
你不想吗
You don't want it?
一天之前
A day ago,
如果你告诉我将会站在这个舞台上...
if you told me I'd be standing on this stage...
不  我做不到 佛农
No,I can't do it,Vernon.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
查利死了
Charlie's gone.
查利在天之灵  希望你继续
Charlie would have wanted you to go on.
难得的机会
This is your shot.
我们的机会
It's our shot.
真的
Really?
这是查利所希望的吗
This is what charlie would have wanted?
他死了
Charlie's dead.
喂  他也是我的挚友
Hey,he was my friend,too,you know.
这样对待朋友  太卑鄙
It's a hell of a way to treat a friend.
你又在说什么胡话
Again,what are you talking about?
你杀了他  对吧
You killed him,didn't you?
为什么啊
And for what?
那么我...我们可以东山再起吗
So that I --so that we could be back on top?
胡言乱语
That's insane.
不  你吓着我了
No,you're scaring me.
首先是万斯  然后是杰布·德克斯特
First it was vance,then it was jeb dexter.
即便你是为了我  才这样做
Even if you thought you were doing it for me,
但你怎可以杀害查利
How in god's name could you kill charlie?
你疯了
Oh,you are crazy.
你利用我  利用我的魔术杀害他
You used me,and you used my act to do this to him.
杰伊 我不会如此责难他
I wouldn't be so hard on him,jay.
他是无辜的
He didn't do it.
尽是些过气魔术道具
This is just a bunch of old-timey magic stuff --
一点用都没
None of it magic.
没有香草  没有蜡烛  没有塔罗牌
No herbs,no candles,and no tarot cards.
他们要怪我了
I'll be damned.
什么
What?
还认得他吗
Look like anyone we know?
我的神啊
Sweet mary and joseph.
查利
Charlie.
杰伊 真的是我
It's really me,jay.
什么鬼东西...
How the hell...
天啊  你忘了年轻的感觉
God,you forget what it feels like to be young.
太棒了
It's amazing.
你多大了
How old are you?
那要看你是怎么定义"年龄"
Oh,it depends on what you mean by "old."
严格来说  我现在28岁
Right now,technically,about 28,
但其实我来这里有一段时间了
But I've been around a lot longer than that.
多久
How long?
让我有只够时间说服一个巫者
Long enough to have shilled for barnum.
给我某样东西
And he gave me something.
什么
What's that?
秘法书  载有真正魔法的书
The grimoire --a book of real magic.
开始  我还以为是骗人的把戏
At first,I thought it was a scam,
后来  我试用上面的咒语  还凑效了
But then I tried one of the spells,and it worked.
事实上  咒语都当真不假
In fact,they all worked.
我翻到最后一页  记载了一个永生的咒语
So when I got to the end and there was one for immortality...
天啊  查利
My god,charlie.
在表演上  我所表演的戏法
And my show,the things that I can do.
不同的咒语
Different spell.
让你品尝一下万能的滋味
But it gives you a little taste of what's possible.
不  我不建议你碰那个  弗农
Oh,no,i wouldn't touch those,vernon.
它们还散发着魔力
They're --they're still radioactive.
你杀了万斯和杰布·德克斯特
You killed vance and jeb dexter.
什么  难道你以为这是室内游戏吗
What,you think this is a parlor game?
那些混蛋整天挖苦你
You were being humiliated by those punks.
一个过气糟老头无力反抗
A washed-up old man who couldn't even defend himself.
你利用我做如此可怖之事
You used me to do these terrible things.
我用咒语  送你厚礼
I used them to give you a gift.
你不也沾沾自喜吗  你的眼睛出卖了你
And you wanted it,jay. I saw it in your eyes.
我没有那样想过
No,i never wanted this.
你都准备自杀了
You were ready to kill yourself.
我拯救了你
I saved your life.
杰伊  不是吗
Is that right,jay?
我一直在你身边
I was there for you,like I've always been.
一直如此
Like I'll always be.
你们俩  跟我来
Come with me,both of you.
你以为第一轮精彩绝伦吗
You think the first time around was good?
第二轮才是顶峰
The second time's even better.
你已经知道怎么操作  驾轻就熟
All the know-how,none of the aches and pain.
不  别  我不做
No,i won't do this.I won't.
以前  我可没开出这样的条件
I've never made this offer before.
因为  以前我没想过会交到
But,then again,I've never had friends
两你们两人的朋友
Like the two of you before.
让我帮你们
Let me do this for you.
为了我们永生  还有谁需要牺牲
And who else has to die so that we can live forever?
为了永生  究竟要付出多大代价
What's the price tag on immortality?
你所做的一切  都是错的  查利
This isn't right,charlie,what you're doing.
你清楚得很
You know that.
从心底里  你知道
Somewhere,you know that.
我知道  我不要孤独一人
I know I don't want to come back alone,
从新开始
To start all over,alone.
杰伊
Jay...
时光可以倒流
We can be young again.
我们三人  青春健壮
The three of us together --vital and alive...
永生不死
Forever.
别做梦
Not so fast!
我不是贵族  这也不是什么神奇之地
I ain't guttenberg,and this ain't "cocoon."
永生  好把戏啊
Immortality. that's a neat trick.
这不是把戏  是魔术
It's not a trick.it's magic.
快接子弹  我练了好久
Hey,bullet catch --been working on that.
抓他
Get him!
放了他  快
Let him go -- now!
离我和我朋友远远的
Just leave me and my friends alone.
我放弃试用咒语和魔法
All right,i will give it up --the spells,the hexes.
保证  这是最后一次
This is the last time.I promise.
杰
Jay...
你竟然帮着外人
You picked these strangers over me?
还好吧
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
我没事
Yeah,i'm all right.
喂  杰伊
Hey,jay.
我们想说声感谢
We wanted to thank you
谢谢你  昨天救了我们
For what you did yesterday.
昨天  我杀了我的挚友
I killed my best friend yesterday,
你们还谢我
And you want to thank me?
弗农呢
Where's vernon?
他离开了
Oh,he's gone.
因为我对查利所做的一切
He said he didn't want to speak to me again
他说他再也不想跟我说话
after what i did to charlie
杰  你知道  查利永远不会放弃做他想做的事
listen jay,you know,charlie is never gonna give up on what he's doing
永不
ever
你做得对
you did the right thing
你确定吗
are you sure about that
查利犹如我的兄弟
you know charlie was just like me brother
如今  他死了
and now,he's dead
因为我做了对的事
because i did the right thing
他送赠我一份厚礼  我却以怨报德
he offer me the a gift that i just threw it back to his face
现在我终究孤独终老
so now i have to spend the rest of my life old and alone
究竟有哪点对了
what's right about that
杰伊
jay
你的卡片
your cards
不要了
leave them away
不知道你怎么想  我现在想喝酒
i don't know about you buddy,i can go for a beer
我要出去走走
i gonna take a walk
好吧 我加入
okay,i'm in
为何改变主意
what changes your mind